Rick Farouni | Curriculum Vitae

I am currently a doctoral candidate in quantitative psychology at the Ohio State University. I also hold a master's degree in mathematical statistics from OSU. I have excellent skills in scientific computing and a strong background in machine learning, multivariate statistics, and Bayesian statistics. My research is focused both on the statistical analysis of fMRI neuroimaging data and on nonparametric Bayesian modeling of longitudinal and time-series data in psychology.

Education

Academic Qualifications.....

The Ohio State University

PhD in Quantitative Psychology

Advisor: Professor Robert Cudeck

The Ohio State University

Master of Science in Statistics

Ohio, USA
2012-2014

The Ohio State University

Master's Degree in Quantitative Psychology

Thesis Project: 'Latent Variable Modelling of Categorical Item Responses in a Hierarchical Bayesian Framework'

The Pennsylvania State University
Bachelor's Degree in Psychology

Pennsylvania, USA 2011-2012

Ohio, USA

Ohio, USA 2012-2014

2012-Present

Course Projects....

- Multivariate Statistics (STAT 7560): 'Retinotopic Mapping of the Human Visual Cortex Using Independent Component Analysis'
- Advanced Computational Statistics (STAT 7730): 'Bayesian Analysis of Noisy Images Using Markov Random Fields'
- **Statistical Consulting** (STAT 6750): 'Modelling Categorical Perception of Speech Sounds using Beta Regression'

Conference Presentations

Joint Statistical Meetings

O Poster Title: Across-Subject Predictive Modeling of fMRI BOLD Responses to Faces

2015

Awards and Fellowships

Graduate Student Conference Presentation Award

The Ohio State University

The Center for Cognitive and Brain Sciences Summer Graduate Fellowship The Ohio State University	2015
Project Proposal : 'Decoding the Pixels of the Face Image from the Voxels of fMRI BOLD Activity Patterns'	
The Social and Behavioral Sciences Summer Fellowship The Ohio State University	2014
Oniversity Fellowship The Ohio State University	2012
Experience	
Teaching Experience	
• Graduate Teaching Associate The Ohio State University Teaching Assistant for Psychology 2220: Data Analysis in Psychology	Ohio, USA 2013-present
Test Preparation Instructor Instructor of the Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT)	Moscow, Russia 2009-2012
Teacher of English as a Foreign Language Teacher of General and Academic English	Moscow, Russia 2001-2009
Journal Review Service.	
Psychometrika Journal Peer Reviewer	2015
Psychological Methods Journal Peer Reviewer	2015
Computing and Language Skills	
Programming and Software Skills	
 Programming Languages: Proficient in numerical and statistical computing languages working with and transitioning between Julia, R, Python, and Matlab depending o Strong command of probabilistic programming languages such as Stan. Experience learning models. Basic familiarity with statically typed programming languages such a 	n computing goals. ed in building deep
• Computing Tools and Software: Experience with a variety of technologies such as LAB Basic knowledge in website development tools such as HTML, CSS, and Jekyll.	T _E X ,Linux OS, Git.
• Supercomputing: Good knowledge of running numerical analyses on the Ohio Supermain clusters.	computer Center's
Languages	

• English, Arabic, Russian, Spanish (limited)